Would you call yourself lazy?
你会说自己懒吗？
If you live in a messy house and are reluctant to lift a finger to help out, maybe you are.
如果你家里乱糟糟，还不愿伸手帮忙，或许你就是懒。
But laziness is a subjective thing – sloppiness to one person might be a form of relaxation to another.
但懒惰是主观的——对一个人而言的邋遢，对另一个人来说可能是一种放松。
And if you can be bothered to read on, you'll see that opinion is divided on whether laziness is a bad thing.
如果你愿意继续读下去，你会发现人们对懒惰是否是件坏事看法不一。
Generally speaking, we tend to look on our laziness as a negative thing.
一般而言，我们往往将懒惰视为负面事物。
Inertia, slothfulness, idleness and apathy are used as criticisms and insults against individuals and groups of people.
惰性、怠惰、闲散和冷漠常被用来批评、指责个人或群体。
We think of lazy people as unproductive or that they don't really care about things.
我们认为懒惰的人效率低下，或是对事物漠不关心。
And when we find ourselves doing nothing, we feel guilty about it.
当我们自己无所事事时，也会为此感到愧疚。
Could this be because we are not instinctively lazy creatures?
这会不会是因为我们并非天生懒惰的生物？
And is that why we often do things we don't need to do and which are sometimes painful – like running a marathon?
这是不是我们常常去做没必要、甚至有时很痛苦的事的原因——比如跑马拉松？
Writing for BBC Future, Claudia Hammond explains that "enforced and extended rest, unless we are ill and our bodies demand it, leads not to feelings of being relaxed but of restlessness and irritability."
为BBC未来专栏撰稿的克劳迪娅·哈蒙德解释道：“被迫的长时间休息，除非是生病且身体需要，否则不会带来放松感，反而会让人焦躁、易怒。”
Others may suggest we are naturally lazy, and that we can't help taking it easy, though it's hard to believe because we're constantly told to do more.
也有人认为我们天生懒惰，忍不住想放松，尽管这很难让人相信，因为我们总被要求多做事。
But kicking back and living life in the slow lane could be better for our health.
但放松下来、慢节奏生活或许对健康更有益。
A study by psychologist Dr Robert Levine in 1999, for example, concluded that people living in cities with a fast pace of life had the highest rates of coronary heart disease.
例如，心理学家罗伯特·莱文博士1999年的一项研究得出结论，生活在快节奏城市的人患冠心病的概率最高。
Laziness has also been shown to be good for our mental health, so having a nap or some downtime shouldn't be frowned upon.
研究还表明，懒惰对心理健康有益，因此小睡片刻或留点空闲时间不该被诟病。
And there are other possible benefits too.
懒惰还有其他潜在好处。
Dr Masud Husain, Professor of Neurology at the University of Oxford, told the BBC: "We found that people who have tended to be more apathetic might in some ways be more creative, so that although they might be a couch potato, they might be coming up with one great idea that might be very interesting and useful."
牛津大学神经学教授马苏德·侯赛因博士接受BBC采访时表示：“我们发现，性格更冷漠的人在某些方面可能更有创造力，所以即便他们是懒人，也可能想出一个极具趣味和价值的好点子。”
So, in our frenetic lives, maybe we should chill out, get into goblin mode and contemplate the benefits laziness can bring.
因此，在忙碌的生活中，或许我们该放松下来，开启摆烂模式，思考懒惰能带来的好处。